Leonard Carmichael Papers ca.1917-1973 Mss.B.C212
American Philosophical Society
Leonard Carmichael Papers, 1898-1973
Circa 1917-1973
Mss.B.C212
American Philosophical Society
183.0 Linear feet ca. 180,000 items
Leonard Carmichael was a psychologist whose most significant contributions were made in the fields of child psychology and biopsychology. Educated at Tufts and Harvard, he taught at Princeton, Brown, and Rochester, later returning to Tufts to serve as its President from 1938-1952. An outstanding administrator, Carmichael served as executive officer for the Smithsonian Institute from 1952-1964, and was subsequently vice president for research and exploration at the National Geographic Society. In his later years, he served as President of the American Philosophical Society from 1970-1973. This large and varied collection reflects the entire range of Carmichael's prolific career. It includes a variety of types of records, including correspondence, committee reports and records, long series of articles and speeches, drafts of papers and books, and pocket notebooks. All phases of his professional life are covered, from his years in academia, to his time at the Smithsonian Institute and the National Geographic Society, as well as his involvement in a large number of professional organizations.
Carmichael, Leonard, 1898-1973
Bibliography
Corner, George W. "Leonard Carmichael (1898-1973)," American Philosophical Society, Yearbook 1974.
Pfaffmann, Carl, "Leonard Carmichael: November 9, 1898-September 16, 1973," Biographical Memoirs NAS, Vol. 51. (Washington, D.C.: National Academy of Sciences, 1980).
Physiology, Biochemistry, and Biophysics Note
Scholars of physiology, biochemistry, or biophysics may find the following of interest:
Cohn, Edwin J. (Edwin Joseph), 1892-1953 Correspondence (1 item) 1953 English
Related Archival Materials note
Tufts University has 8.75 linear feet of documents primarily relating to Carmichael's tenure (1938-1952) as President of that institution.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by the estate of Dr. Carmichael, 1974.
Scope and Contents note
This voluminous collection reflects the varied and prolific career of Carmichael. It includes a variety of types of records, including correspondence, committee reports and records, long series of articles and speeches, drafts of papers and books, and pocket notebooks (ca. 500 pp.). Significant and more voluminous material consists of series relating to professional organizations of which he was a member or officer. These include: American Association for the Advancement of Science, American Academy of Arts and Sciences, American Association of Museums, American Council of Education, American Psychological Association, Brookings Institution, College Entrance Examination Board, Committee of New England, Educational Testing Service, National Academy of Sciences, National Research Council, National Science Foundation, and the National Trust for Historic Preservation.
There is significant material for the Tufts period, post 1938, including reports, committee meetings, and correspondence. There are similar types of material for his student years at Harvard; and his teaching time at Princeton and Brown, but less material for his time at the University of Rochester. There is also material on the Society for Research in Child Development. Outside the academic world he functioned in various capacities, all producing significant series within his papers. There is a great deal of materials for his period at the Smithsonian Institution, but less for his tenure at the National Geographic Society.
There is a sizable group of material for the Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory at Bar Harbor, Maine, and also for his work as an editorial adviser for psychology at Houghton Mifflin Company. Of further note are the over 150 folders concerning animals, from antelope to zebra, which present his research into their development and behavior. Also of significance is the material on the use of motion pictures in psychology. Lastly are the eleven bound volumes of papers written by Carmichael's psychology students at Brown and Rochester University from 1932-1938. These are grouped under the subject headings: Audition, Emotion, Endocrinology, Learning, The Lower Senses, Perception, Response, Thought and Language and Vision.
Biographical/Historical note
Leonard Carmichael was born November 9, 1898 in the Germantown section of Philadelphia. His parents were Thomas Harrison Carmichael, a physician, and Emily Henrietta Leonard Carmichael, a graduate of Wellesley College. His maternal grandfather, Charles Hall Leonard, was Dean of the Crane Theological School of Tufts University, a fact that presages Carmichael's long association with that university.
Trained as a psychologist in the early years of this field, he also pursued research in zoology and biology. Carmichael's greatest contributions were in the areas of child psychology and biopsychology, with a special emphasis on the importance of genetic determinants of behavior. He was educated at Tufts (B.S., 1920) and Harvard (Ph.D., 1924) and taught at Princeton (1924-1926), Brown (1926-1936), and Rochester (1936-1938). During his time at Brown, he collaborated with Herbert Jasper in the earliest EEG studies in this country. He was president of Tufts University from 1938-1952, where he was simultaneously Director of the Laboratory of Sensory Physiology and Psychology. In 1946, he published his Manual of Child Psychology, which is considered a milestone in the scientific treatment of human development. The fourteen years he spent at Tufts were a time of great expansion in facilities, finances, and enrollment. One of his most important jobs was guiding the University's activities through the WWII time period.
Carmichael left Tufts in 1952 to become the executive officer of the Smithsonian Institute, a position he held until 1964. During his tenure there, he was responsible for the modernization of what was called the "nation's attic." Under his leadership, the Institute greatly expanded, with the creation of the Museum of History and Technology, and the addition of two wings to the Museum of Natural History. He left that position to become Vice President for Research and Exploration for the National Geographic Society. During his time in this position, the Society sponsored a great deal of exciting and ground-breaking research, including the Leakeys' anthropological studies in East Africa, Jane Goddall's work on primate behavior, and the underwater explorations of Jacques-Yves Cousteau.
Carmichael was active in a number of professional organizations, including the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the National Academy of Sciences, and the American Association of Museums. During World War II he headed the National Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel, which recruited scientists and engineers for the war, and later he was Chairman of the Army Scientific Advisory Panel (on Manpower). Carmichael served as chairman of the Division of Anthropology and Psychology of the National Research Council, and he was also a member and chairman of the advisory board of the Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology. He served as president of the American Psychological Association in 1940. The honor of which he was said to be the most proud, however, was his election to the American Philosophical Society in 1942. He served as the President of the Society from 1970 until a few months before his death. Carmichael died September 16, 1973 in Washington, D.C.
The Carmichael Auditorium at the National Museum of History and Technology was dedicated in his name in 1974. But perhaps an even more fitting indication of the lasting impact he made is the Leonard Carmichael Society, still an active volunteer organization at Tufts University. Started in 1958 by Richard Dorsay, it originally consisted of a group of students who would make regular visits to a nearby mental hospital. In the year 2000, it has a volunteer corps of over 1000, a staff of 85, and serves as an umbrella organization for 40 different programs which focus on such issues as homelessness, health, literacy, and youth mentoring. The Leonard Carmichael Society states that "The legacy that this elegant, wise and kind man built throughout his 75 years grows and expands every time Tufts students, faculty members, and staff members join LCS in the belief that they too can change the world."
Abel, Theodora Mead, 1899-1998; Adams, James P. (James Pickwell), 1895-1969; Allport, Gordon W.(Gordon Willard), 1897-1967; American Association of Museums.; American Council of Education; American Psychological Association.; Angulo y González, Armando Wandegército, 1900-; Arnold, Frederic Bartlett, Sir; Arnold, Samuel Tomlinson, 1892-1956; Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 1888-1970; Beck, Lester F. (Lester Fred), 1909-; Beebe-Center, John Gilbert, 1897-1958; Boring, Edwin Garrigues, 1886-1968; Bray, Charles William, 1904-; Brookings Institute; Brown University; Bush, Vannevar, 1890-1974; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944; Conant, James Bryant, 1893-1978; Corner, George Washington, 1889-1981; Craig, Wallace; Cruikshank, Ruth M.; Dallenbach, Karl M., 1887-1971; Ducasse, Curt John, 1881-1969; Educational Testing Service.; Fernberger, Samuel Weiller, 1887-1956; Gates, Louise W.; Gilbert, Roger; Goldfarb, Alvin I.; Guthrie, Edwin R. (Edwin Ray), 1886-1959; Harvard University. Museum of Comparative Zoology.; Haskins, Caryl Parker, 1908-2001; Hooker, Davenport, 1887-; Houghton Mifflin Company.; Hull, Clark Leonard,, 1884-1952; Hunter, Walter Samuel, 1889-1954; Kennedy, John L.; Koffka, Kurt, 1886-1941; Kuo, Zing Yang, 1898-1970; Laboratory of Sensory Physiology and Psychology; Langfeld, Herbert Sidney, 1879-; Lashley, Karl Spencer, 1890-1958; Marshall, Laurence K.; McFarland, Ross Armstrong, 1901-1976; Morey, Robert; Munn, Norman Leslie, 1902-; Murchison, Carl Allanmore, 1887-; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.); National Geographic Society; National Research Council (U.S.). Division of Anthropology and Psychology.; National Roster of Scientific and Specialized Personnel; National Science Foundation; National Trust for Historic Preservation; Onassis, Jacqueline Kennedy, 1929-1994; Pfaffmann, Carl, 1913-; Pollock, Martha C.; Pratt, Carroll C. (Carroll Cornelius), 1894-; Princeton University.; Roberts, S. Oliver, 1910-; Roscoe B. Jackson Memorial Laboratory.; Schlosberg, Harold, 1904-1964; Skinner, B. F. (Burrhus Fredric), 1904-1990; Smithsonian Institution.; Society for Research in Child Development; Tufts University; U.S. Army. Scientific Advisory Panel; University of Rochester.; Warren, Howard C. (Howard Crosby), 1867-1934; Wendt, George Richard, 1906-1977; Wilson, E. Bright, (Edgar Bright), 1908-1992; Windle, William Frederick, 1898-; Woodworth, Robert Sessions, 1869-1962; Yerkes Laboratories of Primate Biology, Inc.; Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956; Behavior science; Biology; Child development.; Endocrinology; Perception; Psychology; Scientists in World War I; Zoology
- Leonard Carmichael Papers, ca. 1917-1973 (Box 1)
  - Abbey, David S.
  - Abbott, C. D.
  - Abbot, Charles Greeley
    - Garber, Paul E
    - Ripley, S. Dillon
    - Menzel, Donald H
  - Abbott, Donald G
  - Abbott, Everett
  - Abbott, Frederic E., Rev.
  - Abbott, Preston S.
  - Abbott, R Tucker
  - Abel, Theodora M
  - Abelson, Philip H.
  - Abramson, Harold A
  - Academic Career Rejections
    - Fernberger, Samuel W
    - Titchener, E B
    - Givler, Robert Chenault
    - Cousens, John A
    - Holmes, Henry W
    - Allport, Floyd H
    - Richtmyer, F K
    - Gill, R C
    - Kruse, P J
    - Works, George A
    - Dearborn, Walter H
    - Sanderson, Dwight
    - Payne, Bruce R
    - Miner, J B
    - Adams, J P
    - Ogden, R M
    - Neilson, W A
    - Spaulding, F E
    - Boring, E G
    - Moore, Clifford H
    - Murchison, Carl
    - Mead, A D
    - Langfeld, Herbert S
  - Academic Costume
  - Academic Honors, 1928-33
  - Academic Honors, 1933-34
  - Academic Honors, 1934-36
  - Academic Press
    - Bittig, Carol H
  - Academic Standing - Committee on
  - Academy of Medicine, Washington, D.C.
  - Academy of Political Science
  - Accokeek Foundation
  - "Aceace"
    - Perez, Gabriel Garcia
  - Ach, N
  - Achilles, Paul S
  - Achilles, Theodore Carter
  - Acker, John Edward
  - Ackerman, Arthur W
  - Ackerman, Robert E
  - Acta Psychologica Keijo
  - Acton, Gladys
  - Adams, Arthur S
  - Adams, C R
  - Adams, Donald K
  - Adams, E James
    - Baker, Robert C
  - Adams, Henry F
  - Adams, Howard
  - Adams, J W
  - Adams, James P
  - Adams, Mrs. James P
  - Adams, John P
  - Adams, Joseph P
  - Adams, Lois
  - Adams, Mrs. Rachel
  - Adams, Raymond D
  - Adams, Russell B
  - Adam's Rib Restaurant
    - Faraclas, John E
  - Adenauer, Konrad
  - Adkins, Dorothy C
  - Adler, Helmut E
  - Adrian
  - Aero Club of Washington
    - Adams, Joseph P
  - Aerospace Medical Ass'n.
  - Aesthetics
  - Aesthetics and Psychology
    - Goodrich, Lloyd
  - Affection
  - African Research and Development Co., Inc.
  - Afshar, H K
  - Aggression
  - Agriculture in New England
  - Aguas, A. de Oliveira
  - Aguirre, Emiliano, S J
  - Aibs Education Review
  - Aiken, Herbert Austin
  - Ainsworth, Mrs. Roy C
  - Air Force Association
  - Air Force Museum
  - Air Force Museum Foundation, Inc.
    - McKnew, Thomas W
    - McConnell, J P
    - Grant, L J
    - Grosvenor, M B
    - Kettering, E W
  - Airlie Foundation
  - Akeley, Carl
    - Salseth, David K
    - Dr. Payne
  - Akers, Floyd D
  - Akin, Ted M
  - Akre, Charles T
  - Alabama, University of
    - Thompson, James A
  - Alaska Geographical Society
  - Alba, Jaime
  - Albright, Alan B (Caribbean Research Institute)
  - Albright, Alan B (C.R.I.)
  - Albright, William Foxwell
  - Albright, Mrs. William F
  - Alcoa Seaprobe
    - Hobbs, F Worth
    - Snider, Ed
  - Alden Foundation, Inc. (Mrs. Bonnie Alden Phillips)
  - Aldine Publishing Company
  - Aldred, F D
  - Aldred, F W
  - Aldrich, Emma B
  - Aldrich, Mrs. Helen M
  - Aldrich Chemical Company, Inc.
  - Alee, W C
  - Alexander, Charles P
  - Alexander, D D
  - Alexander, Edward P
  - Alexander Hamilton Bicentennial Commission
  - Alfalfa Club
    - Bredin, J Bruce
    - Trew, Shirley M
    - Dinner Ctte., Alfalfa Club
    - Bell, William T
    - Walters, Velma I
    - Gardner, John W
    - Beers, Thomas M
    - Oliphant, S Parker
    - Mr. Sanders
    - Brown, J Carter
    - Weber, C Swan
    - Jennings, Lewellyn A
  - Alfred University
  - Algonquin Club of Boston
    - Mock, Harold A
    - Thompson, Cameron
    - Haller, Julius F
    - Manager, Algonquin Club
    - Kittredge, Wheaton
  - Ali-Aba-Cle Review
  - Allen, Betty
  - Allen, Clarence E
  - Allen, Faith
  - Allen, Mary K
  - Allen, Myron S
  - Allen, R D
    - Varney, Charles E
    - Wish, Fred D, Jr.
    - Gentry, C B
    - Nooton, F C
    - Verdlanck, F A
    - MacBride, Bessie
    - Young, Edward S
    - Haggard, Roy S
    - White, Helen M
  - Allen, Robert F, Jr.
    - Reymers, Lynda A
  - Allentwon Art Museum
  - Allgrove, Arthur Eames
  - Alliance in Art
    - Kreeger, Mrs. David Lloyd
  - Allighan, Garry
  - Allport, Floyd H
  - Allport, Gordon W
  - Alpert, George
  - Alpert, Richard
  - Alpha Omega Alpha Honor Medical Society
  - Alschbach, Philip A
  - Alter, Chester M
  - Althin, Torsten
    - Marbach, Ruth Ann
  - Altiere, Edward S A
  - Altman, Joseph
  - Altmann, Stuart
  - Alyea, Hubert N
  - Amalaraj, A
  - Amazon Research Center
  - Ambassador Club
  - Ambrosia, Sister
  - Amen, Elisabeth W
  - America - Israel Society
    - Cassidy, George
  - America's Young Men
    - Howes, Durward
  - Amer. Ass'n Advancement of Sci., 1934
    - McGeoch, John A
    - Ward, Henry B
    - Anderson, John E
    - Woodley, Samuel
    - Dashiell, John F
    - Dunlap, Knight
    - Gray, William S
    - Hargan, James
    - Miles, Walter R
    - Ingraham, Mark H
    - Anderson, John E
    - Dwight, Charles A S
    - Johnson, H M
    - Watkins, Ralph J
    - Buswell, G T
    - Hull, Clark L
    - Gates, Arthur I
    - Allport, F H
    - Davis, Charles
    - Porter, James P
    - Shepherd, William T
    - Wickland, Carl A
    - Woodrow, Herbert
    - Riddell, Newton
    - Wagner, Mazie Earle
    - Fernald, Grace M
    - Blakeslee, Albert F
    - Thorndike, Edward L
    - Root, William T
    - Schoen, Max
    - Hunter, Walter S
    - Richards, T W
    - Blakely, Clarence L
  - Am. Assoc. Adv. of Sci. Annual Meeting, 1958
    - Adams, Arthur S
    - Taylor, Raymond L
    - Brode, Wallace R
    - Emery, Alden H
    - Lindsay, G Carroll
    - Dunn, R Roy
    - Stephens, Thomas E
    - Killian, James R
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    - Ball, Mabel Frothingham
    - Davis, Tenney L
    - Campbell, C Macfie
    - Boring, E G
    - Lewis, C I
    - Davis, T L
    - Clark, Walter Eugene
    - Oleson, Alexandra
    - Branch, Claude R
    - Sutherland, Arthur E
    - Mead, Leonard C
    - Voss, John
    - Hoagland, Hudson
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Edsall, John T
    - Phillips, Henry B
    - Romer, Alfred S
    - Holton, Gerald
    - Land, Edwin H
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences -- Nominations an New Memberships
    - Brewer, George F
    - Burhoe, Ralph W
    - Wessell, Nils Y
    - Greene, William C
    - Burchard, John Ely
    - Wilson, Edwin B
    - Harrison, George R
    - Hoagland, Hudson
    - Stewart, Robert B
    - Sachar, Abram Leon
    - Land, Edwin H
  - American Academy of Neurology
    - Bailey, Pearce
    - Imus, Henry A
    - Swedien, Thomas D
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science
  - American Airlines
  - American Art League, Inc.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science
    - Godfrey, Kneeland A., Jr.
    - Deason, Hilary J
    - Trew, Shirley
    - Campbell, Louise
    - Backstrom, James R
    - Wolfle, Dael
    - Abelson, Philip H
    - Burtt, Harold E
    - McGill, Thomas E
    - Seeger, Raymond J
    - Branscomb, Lewis M
    - Henderson, Mr.
    - Butler, James C
    - Wolff, Kathryn
    - Deason, Hilary J
    - Sommer, Richard G
    - Reymers, Lynda A
    - McGeoch, John A
    - Anderson, John E
    - Woodley, Sam
    - Watkins, Ralph
    - Cattell, James McKeen
    - Gray, William S
    - Booth, Windsor Peyton
    - Cantrell, Lawson J
    - Taylor, Raymond L
    - Dunn, R Roy
    - Siddons, F P H
    - Oehser, Paul H
    - Owen, Ed W
    - Du Shane, Graham
    - Klopsteg, Paul E
    - Behnke, John A
    - Dearborn, Walter
    - Waterman, Mrs. Alan T
    - Leake, Chauncey D
    - Billman, Carl
    - Berry, William
    - Robinson, E S
    - Ward, Henry B
    - Keller, Fred S
    - Bills, Arthur G
    - Ogden, Robert M
    - Shipton, W D
    - Ingraham, Mark H
    - Miles, Walter R
    - Ruckmick, Christian A
    - Dallenbach, Karl M
    - Roos, Mary M
    - Stone, Calvin P
    - Tucker, A C
    - Woodrow, Herbert
    - Wheeler, Raymond H
    - Darrow, Chester W
    - Thorndike, Edward L
    - Boder, David P
    - Nafe, John Paul
    - Higginson, G D
    - Blakeslee, Albert F
    - Freeman, Frank N
    - Ledgerwood, Richard
    - Elliott, R M
    - Gilliland, A R
    - Reed, H B
    - Stroud, J B
    - Whitely, Paul L
    - Cole, Lawrence W
    - Conklin, E S
    - Hoisington, L B
    - Lanier, Lyle H
    - Miner, J B
    - Rexroad, Carl N
    - Robinson, M F
    - Waters, R H
    - Stone, Calvin P
    - Cason, Hulsey
    - Dingwall, Ewen C
    - Mitchell, James M
  - American Association of Geographers
  - American Association of Museums
    - Patterson, Joseph Allen
    - Mr. Payne
    - Alderson, William T
    - Barney, Laura D
    - Hammond, Frank H
    - Pringle, George H
    - Bittig, Carol H
    - Yecies, Susan M
    - McGrath, Kyran M
    - Brown, James M III
    - Bentley, Mr.
    - Alexander, Edward P
    - Coleman, Laurence Vail
    - Bookstein, Irving
    - McDaniel, Joseph M, Jr.
    - Jones, Louis C
    - Mauzy, Wayne L
    - Rainey, Froelich
    - Grobman, Arnold B
    - Heinrich, Theodore Allen
    - Hatt, Robert T
    - Nagel, Charles
    - Morley, Grace L McCann
    - Reed, Gervais
    - Crouch, Philbrick M
    - Milliken, William M
    - Brew, J O
    - Coffey, Katherine
    - Zepp, Erwin C
    - Watson, Thomas, Jr.
    - Hammond, Frank H
    - Taube, Mortimer
    - Copeland, Mrs. Lammot Du Pont
    - Lloyd, George W
    - Herzog, Henry W
    - Harris, Paul S
    - Kingman, Eugene
    - Rodney, James D
    - Crittenden, Christopher
    - Dulles, John Foster
    - Herdeck, Donald E
    - McCardle, Carl W
    - Stout, George L
    - Grobman, Arnold B
    - Morley, Grace L MCCann
    - Burton, E Milby
    - Netting, M Graham
    - Welch, Robert C
    - Zamoshkin, A
    - Smith, James Kellum
    - Hatch, John Davis, Jr.
    - Mather, Kirtley F
    - Romer, Alfred S
    - Dorra, Henri
    - Turnham, Mrs. Alice J
    - Brown, Henry D
    - Fuller, Richard E
    - Still, John S
    - Finley, David E
    - Nixon, Richard M
    - Lever, Michael
    - Buckley, Charles E
    - Montgomery, Charles F
    - Kingman, Eugene
    - Bridaham, Lester B
    - Vail, R W G
    - Hatch, John Davis, Jr.
    - Easby, Dudley T, Jr.
    - Roberts, H Radclyffe
    - Cairns, Huntington
    - Adams, E James
  - American Association of School Administration
  - American Association of State Psychology Boards
    - Terris, Lillian D
  - American Association of University Professors
    - Adams, C R
    - Damon, L T
    - Himstead, Ralph E
  - American Association of University Women
  - American Atheists, Inc.
  - American Book Company
  - American Book Publishers Council, Inc.
  - American Business and Professional Trust
  - American College Bureau
  - American Committee to Preserve Abu Simbel
    - McCullough, Max.
  - American Council for Higher Education
    - Wilson, Logan
    - Dobbins, Charles G
  - American Council on Education
    - Zook, George F
    - Miller, George S
    - Conant, James Bryant
    - Brown, Francis J
    - McGrath, Earl J
    - Fuller, Edgar
    - Johnson, Louis
    - Walters, Raymond
    - McDonald, Ralph
    - Brumbaugh, A J
    - Tolley, William P
    - Day, E E
    - Donovan, H L
    - Chase, Henry W
    - Friley, Charles E
    - Hill, Henry H
    - Malott, Deane W
    - Morrill, J L
    - Robbins, Frank E
    - Stoddard, George D
    - Horton, Mildred McA
    - Fine, Benjamin
    - Howes, Raymond P
    - Cahill, George A
    - Davidson, Carter
    - Little, Dr. J. Kenneth
    - Adams, Arthur S
    - Toepelman, W C
    - Lunden, L R
    - Minutes of Meetings, [Ctte. on Relationships of Higher Education to the Fed. Gov't.], February 5 and March 5, 1971.
    - Waterman, Alan T
    - Mather, J Paul
    - Morrill, J L
    - Howes, Raymond F
    - Wann, Harry A
    - Thackrey, Russell I
    - Distler, Theodore A
    - Howes, R H
    - Anderson, Hurst R
    - Broughton, Robert W
    - Stone, Donald C
    - Hussey, Fred G
    - Wilson, Logan
    - West, Elmer D
    - Dobbins, Charles G
    - Boozer, Howard R
    - Hauck, Arthur A
    - Reed, Robert H
  - American Elsevier Publishing Company
  - American Engineer
  - American Enterprise Institute
  - American Ethnological Society, Inc.
    - Lesser, Alexander
  - American Federation of Arts
    - Pope, John A
    - Prior, Harris K
  - American Federation of Teachers
    - Davis, Jerome
  - American Foundation for the Blind, Inc.
    - Holopigian, Charles
  - American Geographical Society
    - Payne, Melvin
    - Korff, Serge
    - Grosvenor, Melville B
    - Wood, Walter A
    - Winkler, Kay
    - Snider, Edwin W
    - Adkinson, Burton W
  - American Guidance Service, Inc.
  - American Heritage
    - Ketchum, Richard M
  - American Humanist Association
    - Huber, Elizabeth P
  - American Institute for Economic Research
  - American Institute for Research
    - Flanagan, John C